lloydspharmacy.com 2018-10-23

# Privacy Policy | LloydsPharmacy

###### About Us

This privacy policy explains what information we collect about you, how we and our group may use it, and the steps we take to ensure that it is kept secure. We also explain your rights and how to contact us.

Please note, this website may contain links to other websites which are provided for your convenience. We are only responsible for the privacy practices and security of this site. BY USING THIS WEBSITE AND GIVING YOUR INFORMATION TO US, YOU INDICATE YOUR CONSENT TO US, OUR GROUP AND THIRD PARTIES COLLECTING AND USING YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION IN ACCORDANCE WITH THE TERMS SET OUT IN THIS POLICY. 

LloydsPharmacy will not sell your personal details to anyone. We may use your information to contact you about relevant services or products from our group companies. 

###### Freedom of Information

As a provider of services to the National Health Service, LloydsPharmacy Limited is a public authority for the purposes of the Freedom of Information Act 2000 and the Freedom of Information (Scotland) Act 2002. These Acts impose on us a legal obligation to provide information to anybody making a request through an approved publication scheme (in England this is also known as a Guide to Information). The general presumption is that information relating to our public services must be disclosed. However, there are a number of exemptions set out in the relevant Act which enable us to limit what we provide.

The publication scheme is a complete guide to the information routinely made available to the public by LloydsPharmacy Limited. It is a description of the classes of information about our pharmacists and pharmacies which we make publicly available. 

_Please click here for our Publication Scheme Guide to Information which is made under the Freedom of Information Act 2000._.pdf)[ _Please click here for our Publication Scheme which is made under the Freedom of Information (Scotland) Act 2002._](http://www.itspublicknowledge.info/YourRights/YourRights.aspx)

###### The personal data we collect 

In order to provide you with the services you require, we will collect personal information about you from our website, telephone conversations, emails and written and verbal communications. These will include, for example, your name, address, email address, phone number and details that are relevant to the service(s) in which you are interested. Further details of the personal data we collect are as follows: 

  * If you have a web account with us: your name, gender, date of birth, billing/delivery address, orders and receipts, email and telephone numbers. For your security, we’ll also keep an encrypted record of your login password
  * Details of your interactions with us through contact centres, in store, online or by using one of our apps
  * Information gathered by the use of cookies in your web browser. To deliver the best possible web experience, we collect technical information about your internet connection and browser as well as the country, where your computer is located, the pages viewed during your visit, the advertisements you clicked on, and any search terms you may enter on our platform. Learn more about how we use cookies and similar technologies on our [_cookies policy page_](http://www.lloydspharmacy.com/en/info/cookies)
  * Details of your visits to our website and which site you came to us from
  * Personal details which help us to recommend areas of interest
  * Payment card information
  * Your image may be recorded on CCTV when you visit a shop or car park
  * Your social media username, if you interact with us through those channels, to help us respond to your comments, questions or feedback
  * Information about other people: if you provide information to us about any person other than yourself, you must ensure that they understand how their information will be used and that you are authorised to disclose it to us, and to consent to its use on their behalf, before doing so.

###### Cookies

In common with many other website operators, we may use standard technology called 'cookies' on this site. Cookies are small pieces of information that are stored by your browser on your computer's hard drive and they are used to record how you navigate this website on each visit.

Our cookies are used to enable us to develop our website to reflect our customers interests and by noting who has seen which pages, properties and advertisements (including click through from emails), how frequently particular pages are visited and determining the most popular areas of our website. We may use cookies to enrich your experience of using the website by allowing us to tailor what you see to what we have learned about your preferences during your visits to the site.

Most browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually change your browser to prevent cookies being stored. Please note, if you do turn cookies off this will limit the service that we are able to provide to you and may affect your visitor experience.

For further information on cookies and how to switch them off see 

###### How we will use your Information

All personal information, including where carts are abandoned and where personal information is obtained about you and/or any other person whose details you provide will be recorded, used, and protected by us in accordance with current data protection legislation, our Terms and Conditions and this Privacy Policy.

We will primarily use the personal information:

  * To process any orders that you make by using our websites, apps or in store. If we don’t collect your personal data during checkout, we won’t be able to process your order and comply with our legal obligations.
  * To respond to your queries, refund requests and complaints. Handling the information you sent enables us to respond effectively. We may also keep a record of these to inform any future communication with us and to demonstrate how we communicated with you throughout. We do this on the basis of our contractual obligations to you, our legal obligations and our legitimate interests in providing you with the best service. With your consent, we will use your personal data, preferences and details of your transactions to keep you informed by email, web, text, telephone and through our contact centres about relevant products and services including tailored special offers, discounts, promotions, events, competitions and so on. Of course, you are free to opt out of hearing from us by any of these channels at any time.
  * To send you relevant, personalised communications by post in relation to updates, offers, services and products. We’ll do this on the basis of our legitimate business interest.
  * To administer any of our prize draws or competitions which you enter, based on your consent given at the time of entering.
  * To process your booking/appointment requests (for example, our in-store services booking form)
  * To communicate with you in the event that any services requested are unavailable or if there is a query or problem with your order
  * To carry out market research so that we can improve the services we offer
  * To create an individual profile for you so that we can enhance your user experience, to understand and respect your preferences and to provide details of relevant offers and opportunities where you have agreed to receive them
  * To capture your product reviews, for example when you buy goods and services from us we may follow it up with an enquiry about your experience of the product to help us gauge customer satisfaction. You are not obligated to leave reviews and ratings but this facility would enable you to get your views of the product across should you wish to do so.
  * To disclose your personal information. In order to provide our products and services, we may, occasionally, appoint other organisations to carry out some of the processing activities on our behalf. These may include, for example, our panel of medical experts, technology hosts, printing companies and mailing houses. In these circumstances, we will ensure that personal information is properly protected and that it is only used in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

###### Offers And Opportunities

We would like to contact you and/or any person whose information you provide to us, to tell you and/or them about offers and opportunities that are available and about a range of other initiatives in a number of ways, including by post, telephone, text/picture/video message or by email. 

Details of how to opt-in to receiving details of offers are on relevant pages of this website. You can change your/their mind at any time (see the section "How to contact us" below). 

###### Disclosure of your Personal Data

There are circumstances where we wish to disclose or are compelled by law to disclose your personal data to third parties. This will only take place in accordance with the applicable law and for the purposes listed above. These scenarios include disclosure to: 

  * our subsidiaries, branches or associated offices;
  * our Group companies who may contact you by email, phone or post about other products and services (including those from other organisations) in which you may be interested (where you have consented to such communication);
  * manufacturers, including those identified on our Website, who have a relationship or contract with you for the purposes of providing rebates on the Goods you buy from our managed stocks;

our outsourced service providers or suppliers to facilitate the provision of our products and/or services to you, for example: 

  * our panel of medical experts, printing companies and mailing houses;
  * manufacturers of the Goods in the efforts to understand customer preferences, ensure satisfactory stock levels, to improve products and services and to calculate any volume discounts or rebates which may be applicable to your account;
  * our data centre provider for the safe keeping of your personal data, webhosting provider through which your personal data may be collected; and
  * identity verification partners in order to verify your identity against public databases;
  * in these circumstances, we will ensure that your personal data is properly protected and that it is only used in accordance with this Privacy Policy;
  * our nominated third party credit agencies to derive a credit score which will be applied to managing your account. We may also carry out credit checks with licensed credit agencies on your guarantors (if applicable). A record of the search may be kept by us and the agencies;
  * buying groups of which you are a member, in order to communicate with them on the orders you have placed;
  * our advertising partners who enable us to deliver personalised ads to your devices or similar advertising;
  * subject to your consent, to our marketing partners, who may contact you by post, email, telephone, SMS or by other means. If you do not wish to be contacted, you may unsubscribe by clicking “unsubscribe” in the message concerned;
  * analytics and search engine providers that assist us in the improvement and optimisation of our Website. Your personal data is generally shared in a form that does not directly identify you;
  * third party service providers and consultants in order to protect the security or integrity of our business, including our databases and systems and for business continuity reasons;
  * another legal entity, on a temporary or permanent basis, for the purposes of a joint venture, collaboration, financing, sale, merger, reorganisation, change of legal form, dissolution or similar event. In the case of a merger or sale, your personal data will be permanently transferred to a successor company;
  * public authorities where we are required by law to do so;
  * if required, in order to receive legal advice; and
  * any other third party where you have provided your consent.

###### Security

We take the security of personal information seriously. We employ security technology, including firewalls, and Secure Socket Layers to safeguard information and have procedures in place to ensure that our paper and computer systems and databases are protected against unauthorised disclosure, use, loss and damage. 

###### Retention of Personal Data

Your personal data will be retained until your last use of our services and normally for a period of three years thereafter, unless longer retention is required by applicable local law or where we have a continued legitimate and lawful purpose to do so. However, we will not retain beyond this period any of your personal data that is no longer required for the purposes set out in this Privacy Policy. The retention of your personal data will be subject to periodic review. We may keep an anonymised form of your personal data, which will no longer refer to you, for statistical purposes without time limits, to the extent that we have a legitimate and lawful interest in doing so. 

###### International Transfer of Personal Data

We may transfer your personal data to a third party in countries outside the country in which it was originally collected for further processing in accordance with the purposes set out above. In particular, your personal data may be transferred throughout our Group and to our outsourced service providers located abroad. In these circumstances we will, as required by applicable law, ensure that your privacy rights are adequately protected by appropriate technical, organisation, contractual or other lawful means. For a copy of the safeguards which we have put in place to protect your personal data and privacy rights in these circumstances, see the contact details below. 

###### Updating and Correcting Information

You may update or correct your personal information online in the My Account area or by contacting us in writing or by email (see the section "How to contact us" below). Please include your name, address and/or email address when you contact us as this helps us to ensure that we accept amendments only from the correct person. 

We encourage you to promptly update your personal information if it changes. If you are providing updates or corrections about another person, we may require you to provide us with proof that you are authorised to provide that information to us. 

###### Your Rights to Access Your Personal Information

You have the right to receive a copy of the personal information that we hold about you. The same right applies to any other person whose personal information you provide to us. 

###### How To Contact Us

Telephone: 02476 432 400. Calls from a landline will be charged at standard rate. Costs from mobiles may vary.

Email: 

Mail:  
Data Protection Officer  
Lloyds Pharmacy Limited  
Sapphire Court  
Walsgrave Triangle  
Coventry  
CV2 2TX 

###### Changes To This Privacy Policy

Privacy laws and practice are constantly developing and we aim to meet high standards. Our policies and procedures are, therefore, under continual review. We may, from time to time, update our security and privacy policies and suggest that you check this page periodically to review our latest policies.
